Register of the South African subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- DEMOCRATIC RULE, 1994-1995
  - Conference, African National Congress
  - Constitution, South Africa
  - Economy
    - Agriculture (Box 40)
    - General
    - Taxation
  - Education
    - General
    - Freedom of Expression Institute (FXI)
    - South African University Students' Representative Council (SRC)
    - University of Witwatersrand
  - Election, 1994
    - General
      - Ballot papers and tally sheets
      - Clippings
      - Fact sheet
      - Flyers
      - Handbook
      - List for National Assembly and Regional Legislatures
      - Manuals
      - Newsletters (Box 41)
      - Pamphlet
      - Printed matter
      - Preparation for election
      - Reports and updates
      - Voter's guide
  - Housing
  - Human rights
  - Women
  - Miscellany
- MISCELLANEOUS FILE, 1986-1994
  Brochures, flyers, clippings, newsletters, and printed matter relating to the various aspects of life in South Africa.
  - General (Box 42)
  - Clippings
  - Newsletter
  - Printed matter
- MEMORABILIA, 1994
  Tee shirts and other souvenirs relating to the election of 1994.
  - Campaign materials from election 1994,including tee shirts and tie (Box 43-45)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS, 1957-1994 (Boxes 46, 70)
  Includes sample ballot papers; calendars published by the African National Congress, the American Committee on Africa, the Open School on the Move, and the Holland Committee on Southern Africa; flyers and newspapers from various student organizations at the University of Cape Town and the University of Witwatersrand; printed matter and photographic reproductions of Nelson Mandela.
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1984-1987
  - Videotape cassettes
    - "African National Congress: A Time For Candor," n.d. (Cassette 1)
    - "Freedomfest Concert; Observation of Nelson Mandela's Birthday," Two videotape cassettes (Cassette 2-3)
    - "Kwazulu-Natal Indaba,", 1987 (Cassette 4)
    - "Mongane Wally Serote,", n.d. (Cassette 5)
    - "Revolution and Betrayal: The Accelerating Onslaught Against South Africa,", 1986 (Cassette 6)
    - "South Africa: The Mainstay of the Southern African Region,", 1986 (Cassette 7)
    - "Sun City: Artists United Against Apartheid,", 1985 (Cassette 8)
    - "Year of the Struggle," Two videotape cassettes, 1986. (Cassette 9-10)
    - Voteburgers! A Voter Education Guide, n.d. (Cassette 11)
    - "Your Right to Vote", In English, 1993. (Cassette 12)
  - Phonotape reel. "Now's the Time," the Progressive Federal Party, undated (Reel 1)
  - Phonotape cassettes
    - "Amandla," African National Congress, 1986 (Phonotape-cassette 1)
    - "Forces Favourites," End Conscription Campaign (Phonotape-cassette 2)
    - "Fosatu Worker Choirs,", n.d. (Phonotape-cassette 3)
    - NP Liedjies gesing en gekomponeer deur Peter Marais, National Party Election Songs, Election In Afrikaans, 1994. (Phonotape-cassette 4)
    - "Nelson Mandela," Youssou N'Dour, 1986 (Phonotape-cassette 5)
    - Pan African Congress for Real Freedom, 1994 (Phonotape-cassette 6)
    - "Radio Freedom," African National Congress and the People's Army Umkhonto We Sizwe (Phonotape-cassette 7)
    - "Sophiatown," songs from Sophiatown and other plays, 1988 (Phonotape-cassette 8)
    - "South Africa: Time Out For Realism, the Story the Media Refuses to Reveal,", 1986 (Phonotape-cassette 9)
    - "White Wind, Black Tide," Anti-Apartheid Movement (Phonotape-cassette 10)
  - Phonorecords
    - "Amandla," African National Congress, 1980 (Disc 1)
    - "Amandla, Cultural Group," African National Congress, 1987 (Disc 2)
    - "Baboondaogs,", 1986 (Disc 3)
    - "Forces Favourites," End Conscription Campaign (Disc 4)
    - "Give Praise where Praise is Deserved: A Tribute Album to Our Nobel Prize Winner Bishop Desmond Tutu,", 1985 (Disc 5)
    - "Kick Over the Statues! Azania Coming Soon,", 1985 (Disc 6)
    - "Nelson Mandela: Break Down the Door!", 1984 (Disc 7)
    - "South African Trade Union Choirs,", 1985 (Disc 8)
    - "Why You Should Vote NP," personal message from P.W. Botha, 1987 (Disc 9)
- Incremental Materials (Boxes 47-69)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.